Mars Geldard

♀ Roslyn Avenue, Kingston Beach, Tasmania, 7050 □ +61 (0) 431 521 961

■ mail@themartianlife.com | ↑ themartianlife.com | ↑ themartianlife | ★ themartianlife | ★ themartianlife

Professional Summary_____

Career Objectives

I aim to become proficient in a wide range of technologies, expand upon my abilities as a programmer and designer, and add to my experience in mentorship and research. In the pursuit of these goals I hope to always surround myself with opportunities to learn and share my knowledge with others.

CAREER SUMMARY

In the past I have had somewhat varied experience, having been in the workforce for over 8 years before entering tertiary study. Coming from a non-technical background, I quickly found my passion for technology as a way to express my love of mathematics and obsessions with problem-solving and optimisation.

Education

Bachelor of Information and Communication Technology

Mid 2016 - Current

University of Tasmania (UTAS)

Second Year Student

- Bachelor majoring in Software Development
- Electives focusing on Human-Computer Interaction and Research
- Completed 1/3 elite Summer research units: KIT110 under the supervision of Dr Kristy de Salas

Entry requirements for Bachelor's Degree

Start 2016 - Mid 2016

UTAS University Preparation Program

Fast-Tracked

- Completed units on topics such as academic writing, communication and study skills
- Fast-tracked to Bachelor after completing one semester of the 2-semester course

Secondary School/Junior Certificate

2005 - Start 2009

Kimberley College

Left to work

- Completed junior certificate, majoring in the technical stream (Mathematics, Biology, Chemistry, Physics)

Experience____

Bar and Gaming Attendant, Office Assistant

Mid 2012 - End 2015

Sherwood Services Club

Resigned

Initially being hired as a bartender, it was not long before the vast majority of my work was as a gaming cashier, controlling the cash flow within the club, or assisting in the admin/accounts office. My duties as a cashier included swapping money and making change for customers and other areas of the club, counting and sorting tills, making payouts to gaming winners, and assisting managers with all manner of paperwork.

This was fast-paced work that required and bred precision above all else. My time in the admin office had me working both as an office assistant, filing and submitting paperwork, but also dealing with incoming stock, wages and account transactions and their associated software.

Supervisor/Co-ordinator

2009 - Mid 2012

Elstern Imports

Resigned

Starting off at the company when I was 15, I was hired as a casual picker & packer for a wholesale-only jewellery and medical supplies distribution company. In the time that I was there I rose to hire and supervise 4 other staff (and the whole division of our company that dealt with our chain customers), as the company grew to not only have more wholesale customers than ever, but also run 2 retail web-stores.

My daily tasks were overseeing orders and dispatch, generating digital and hand-written invoices, ordering and receiving of stock from our suppliers, taking complaints, inquiries and orders via phone/email/fax, and managing the

September 19, 2017 Mars Geldard Résumé 1

bar-coding and stock systems for our end of the warehouse (including implementing a new system when our number of stock lines outgrew the old one), along with many other unique tasks that would crop up every day.

Awards & Interests_

Prizes	& Participations						
2017	Participant GovHack Hackathon	$GovHack\ Australia$					
2017	Recipient PBest Data Visualisation, Use of Heritage Data & Design Excellence	$GovHack\ Tasmania$					
Memberships							
2016-	Student Member Apple University Consortium	AUC					
2017-	Member Australian Computer Society	ACS					
2017	Member Golden Key International Honour Society	Golden Key					
Volunteering & Conferences							
2016-	Volunteer /dev/world Developer Conference	AUC					
2017	Volunteer Superhero Daughter Day (An intro to STEM for young girls)	Diverse City Careers					
2017	Sponsored Delegate LinuxConf Australia	$Linux\ Australia$					
2017	Delegate New Zealand Gave Developer's Conference	NZGDA					
2016	Volunteer GovHack Hackathon	GovHack					
2016	Volunteer UHack Hackathon	UTAS					
2016	Delegate Buzzconf Technology Festival	Buzzconf					
2016	Delegate Re-imagination Thought Leaders' Summit and Digital Disruptors Awards	ACS					
2016	Attendee Various Melbourne International Games Week events (PAX, GCAP, etc.)	$City\ of\ Melbourne$					
Hobbies & Community Involvement							
2016-	Member University TECH Society (attending networking and workshop events)	UTAS					
2016-	Member Tasmanian University Tabletop Society	UTAS					
Local	Various Groups						

Local Community Member

Various Groups

Tasmanian technology and game development communities

2016 - Current

- Frequent attendee and volunteer at local events, both technical- and networking-focused (e.g. ACS events, TasICT events, independent events held at Enterprize or Factory Floor)
- Member of TasGDS, a society dedicated to facilitating the networking and sharing of ideas among both professional and independent game developers in Tasmania

Referees_

Tony	Gr	ay		
α	,	D	C	

Character Reference - Organiser of /dev/world

Chair, Apple University Consortium 0432 018 441 — a.d.gray@utas.edu.au

Peter Ward

Owner/GM, Sherwood Services Club Reference attached

 $Professional\ Reference\ -\ Previous\ Employer$

Legal Aid Queensland

Valerie Ford Character Reference - Lifelong Family Friend

 $0407\ 594\ 427-vj ford 22@hotmail.com$

September 19, 2017 Mars Geldard Résumé 2